Vaibhav Vijay Front End Developer

■ vaibhavvijay9@gmail.com
+91-8104410870
vaibhavvijay.me
in vaibhavvijay9
vaibhavvijay9

Summary

Front end developer with over 4.5 years of experience in web application development using Angular and JavaScript.

Skills

Technical Skills

Angular 2 and above, NgRx, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SCSS, Angular Material, PrimeNG

Tools and Platforms

VS Code, Git & Github, Chrome DevTools, Lighthouse, Postman, JIRA

Experience

Nagarro, Senior Engineer

Dec 2021 – Present Remote

- Developed and maintained Angular components, screens, and features for a social media platform for health care professionals using Angular 10.
- Collaborated with other developers to implement new features in a way that is consistent with existing codebase conventions.
- Participated in design discussions regarding application architecture, feature implementation, or any other relevant topic as required.
- Lead the development of Admin panel for the application.

Dew Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Software Engineer

Apr 2020 - Dec 2021

Gurugram

- Developed new components and modules using Angular as per client requirements for the application.
- Responsible for maintaining and enhancing the existing code which also included working on AngularJS pages as it is a hybrid application.
- Implemented new features like primeNG library for UI, Internationalization and File handling with S3.

Mindler Education Private Limited, Front-End Developer

Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

New Delhi

- Single-handedly developed from scratch the front-end of a dynamic ed-tech product, *Partner Platform*, using Angular 8 and Bootstrap 4.
- Responsible for all the front-end related tasks of the existing product.
- Developed campaign pages for marketing using HTML and CSS.
- Partner Platform A web application that acts as a SaaS platform for the career counselling process.

Infosys Limited, *Systems Engineer*

May 2018 – Aug 2019

• Worked on Splunk to create dashboards for real time monitoring.

Pune, Maharashtra

- Analysed the logs and then created dashboards that represents the errors in application chain i.e. TIBCO components and Ibis, shows queues status, main frame transfer jobs status, etc.
- Also worked on Ibis Adapter Framework which allows (transactional) messages to be modified and exchanged between different systems. It deals with XML & XSLTs.

Education

Swami Keshvanand Institute of Technology, Jaipur,

2014 - 2018

B. Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

Certificates

FreeCodeCamp/ Responsive Web Design ☑